all right welcome to the solution
raising on voting with your wallet
which is kind of like the consumer side
of the marketing one that we had
previously
um or maybe not we'll let mark decide
more the parameters a solution raises an
hour-long conversation broken up into
three parts we
talk about what it currently looks like
the good the bad and the ugly
what we would love it to look like is
the second part
they don't need to match and then the
third part just the
half of it is um how
is the adjacent possible what we could
actually do now if we had
a large enough threshold of people that
it isn't just
a handful and yet isn't requiring
the world to to come on board before any
kind of real change can happen
so the parameter normally set for
solution is ten thousand people
and a hundred thousand dollars but i am
open to
tweaking that especially in the game b
space where we don't have ten thousand
people
just end sentences like yes
i never really know these formats
like they kind of unsettle me sometimes
because i don't i want to hear what
everybody else
wants to say and there's a lot going on
in my mind but i'm trying to apply it
back so i
i actually hear the most what i can
so the the
the idea is to figure out a way to drive
business to towards those companies that
already
exhibit some kind of game behavior
to nurture
that behavior in the general public and
extinguish
generally gradually the kind of gamey
rivalrous predatory it's more like a
predatory
behavior that gaming companies tend to
do
they keep secrets they
they look for any advantage and there
really is no
there really is no um
immediate reckoning for behavior that
damages a lot of people
so to combat that the idea was having
radical transparency
and something that does as little harm
as possible
little harm is possible i think that
that is for me a a big thing
it seemed to gain a lot of traction when
i put that post in
the idea that if we could find a way
to have people um and i think it was in
in yesterday's group somebody bought up
brought up
well if if i want to vote with my wallet
and i want to
i want to support a company that's doing
good you know like i could just buy that
phone that's gonna
replace the uh the iphone
and i said well what do you know about
that company
and it's well it looks good the the
product looks good
but he said i said you know where they
where they get their products who
they're funded by
what kind of harm they're doing and
where they're getting their goods
manufactured and he couldn't tell me
that
so this would be
something an app would be something
a possibility something that would
immediately give you that information
and it would be
over the long term this is what this
this company has done
this is where it sources all its
materials this is where it's built
this is its impact footing
and even more possibly this is what
everybody makes
and this is where the money goes it's
where it gets money this is where it
goes
everything everything nothing is hidden
so that would be the kind of ultimate so
you could see it
and have a clear picture on
company but this could also be products
so i
i don't want to say too much to narrow
it down because
this is the stage where i want the net
to get
wide so
that um we have a better idea of what
works and what doesn't work and why it
hasn't worked in the past
luckily zoom tells me um i what do
people currently do for this right how
do you decide how to make your purchases
how do you how much do you care what are
the values you put in how much
energy do you put in like what does it
currently look like for you
to vote with your wallet right and
um i can start i have put a lot of time
and energy into caring about
you know is my stuff organic is it fair
trade is it
and at the same time my trust in those
systems is also eroded like even if i
buy fair trade how do i know it's
actually fair trade is it actually
better
than um what else is out there and how
can i
be able to trust that and what i know i
cannot trust is the marketing
that they tell me they're green or they
tell me that they're socially just
i do want a metric and so it would be a
full-time
job just to figure out what i'm gonna
buy what
that's within my my ethics and values
let alone um you know expecting
everybody to do that
but being able to share in that
information is is part of what
i'm very excited for for game b and
these kind of ideas is to be able to
focus
bring that together i do know um part of
what this section also is for is for
again the good the bad and the ugly
what is currently working the space and
part of what mark alluded to
is um that there have been things in the
space that have either failed or haven't
been quite as
picked up by the masses uh the good guy
being the big one that i know of
and they were a good site and i have
used them and they gave you a metric
on the social justice the environmental
and the health impact and um
but they weren't very transparent on
what it was they didn't have
they weren't crowdsourced you couldn't
add new products if you wanted to
and because they weren't transparent and
that you couldn't add your own
products if you and it's its own app
there was a lot of
downfall that this is the space i have
been playing in so i have a lot of ideas
and said i want to give someone else
um chance to share what how do you make
your purchasing decisions
i guess i can go next um
i uh and if we're just talking about
the the goodwill the company not their
like quality of their products because i
do use like consumer reports i do a lot
of research when i'm buying technical
stuff
um uh and i do
tend to buy from companies whose
advertising does claim that
that they have you know free-range
chickens and stuff like that and the
things that i care about
um so if they're signaling to me through
their marketing and advertising then i
am more likely to purchase
if they're um aligning with my
um my kind of i don't know morals
might be one way to put it um
i do not spend a lot of time researching
companies and finding third-party
sources
like uh jubilee was talking about to
validate their marketing
um i you know i do see articles fly by
on social media
that give me an impression of whether or
not i should use a company or not
i am aware that of some specific
situations where those social media
posts were
inaccurate um uh
where i did have to kind of dive in and
decide well am i going to stop using
this tool and then i found out that they
were kind of overblown
and then of course i've seen issues
where a company says that they're doing
all this stuff and they really aren't
so i've seen it kind of both ways i
am not aware of any tools i wasn't aware
of the good guide
uh looks interesting even though it's
not there anymore um
so i don't know of any resources that do
this on that aspect i guess there's a
couple websites on specific issues like
i believe there's there are ways to say
oh is this company
um good for the environment right so
there's there's a couple niche ones that
i think of but i can't think of them on
top of my head i think i've seen them
um so for me
you know i would like something that is
a lot less
friction um you know like jubilee said
it's it's a full-time job
to va to vet every company of every
product you use or most
products or even the expensive products
um
so keeping that simple and easy um
i'd like to be able to contribute it or
maybe we're not onto that part of this
presentation but but yeah right now
today
i don't um i would like to
um so just through osmosis
is kind of how i do those uh get those
opinions so that's today
okay well i don't suppose um i'm
probably the least likely person he
should have here then
because basically you go to tesco's
which is on the corner
and um it's just cheap i have to buy
what's cheap
so so basically and in terms of
sort of like finding companies that are
really good for everything can that
you've got to look
because most most of our see things now
is most of the big corporations
you come in and buy the the green
companies
the companies that are doing good
because people like them so they come in
and buy them
and then there goes that you know what i
mean because it it
you know and there's only a few
companies that own bloody everything
you know i mean so i think i think the
trail
we have behind the company of who owns
them
you know i mean i think i think that
would make a difference um but as i said
i've got a sort of vote
um like this week i'll live off toast
so because i ate shops
even before the the pandaric i wouldn't
go with them anyway you don't i'd avoid
it like to play
you know i mean that i'll just do
without um but
i do well do i don't i i don't know
um but yeah so uh so i think so like
having something that
they could tell you whether the little
bunch of bastards or not they're
just so they put a goody label on
because they think they can get more
sales
you know what i mean and i think i think
that's because there's no trust really
so that's that's as far as i go with
that for this section
but you mark how do you currently do
this what what
meet this need in your life it's it's
very very frustrating for me i i
and i guess that's why i'm i'm so
i feel close ties to this because i feel
like this is a big one
in the game space that
it would be nice to be able to trust
and and and even be able to have a
conversation about
whether windmills are better for the
environment or not
you know where do they get their uh
materials how long does it last
what are the health
health consequences of operating
windmills and things like that
like i don't know i i would like to know
uh all of that information and
be able to call it up from
[Music]
something like google
right now i buy organic i buy local if i
can
and i'm starting to
as a consequence of that because i'm
like somewhat like carrie my
my income has gone down quite a bit but
i've
i've done that so i can concentrate on
writing and
and different things and other things
have happened to you
but uh kind of
made that conscious decision that i want
to be in the space where
it's tilting the word the world towards
a better place
but i'm frustrated in trying to
make that decision like what's what's
good i buy organic eggs i buy
organic vegetables just because in my
mind
organic is better because they're not
using the big chemical company
and that's all i can do now but when
somebody says to me
well organic is just a big scam because
and then they mention a couple of things
well i have no no ground to stand on i'd
like to be able to have
more solid ground but that's what i do
now i
i trust for me is a big thing i can't
trust and transparency and thoroughness
i
i don't really have that but i'm just
doing the best i can
all right so we can switch on to the
next section which is
sharing our vision of a future where
we've solved
this right we have our perfect millions
of dollars of solution as opposed to the
next section we're talking about the
adjacent possible
so would anybody like to start sharing
their vision for the future
it'll mark a shared
i'm happy too if uh people don't mind
um i think and just thinking about
day-to-day purchases
my ideal situation would be i could take
my cell phone
aim it at the huge wall of a thousand of
different
you know i don't eat breakfast cereals
but just take that you know it's a whole
aisle
and see the ratings of them pop up or a
highlight
over the ones that fit my personal
criteria
of companies that um support the world
so you know you can just
basically aim your phone at any product
set
or any other computer with an image of a
product and and
get the rating of that
product or if there's multiple ones have
it highlight the ones that are highest
um for my personal
goals so if i if i value you
for my values um
yeah so that'd be kind of ideal and then
you know if i'm shopping online then you
know have
the same sort of feature um
to where you know you can go in and say
oh this is the product i'm
i'm wanting to buy i'm wanting to buy a
new i'm looking
for new jams or jellies actually i don't
need that either
i have no good examples of stuff i eat
um
a new uh almond flour
which we can talk about how bad almonds
are for the environment but um
and it would then you know take all
those search results that you normally
get from search engines or
from other aggregation sites but it
would filter and sort based upon
the values that i have of the companies
that
produce that and and like carry said
all the way up to chain to that the
company that owns that company and
such and so forth
okay and an ideal future would be the
ev all the all the foods produced and
everything else
will be produced locally so you get to
know in the local community
who's who's doing what where's it where
is
it coming from you can keep them
accountable because you get to know them
so you get to trust them
and then you'll be able to say you know
i recommend these because they're really
good they're doing a lot
for the community nobody owns them up
the chain
and um yeah you get to know but
obviously if you could have something
like bentley said
to have a sort of like a scanner that
could tell you
but as i said you need to to sort like
see
make sure that nobody who was doing the
ratings was getting bought by these
companies
to actually go and sit there and click
forever but um yeah so there'd be none
of that so all the big companies would
go bankrupt
and then everything would revert back to
local and then
you you'd get all the you know so food
wouldn't be getting
taken grown in one place like um
somewhere and then taken to thailand for
the packaging and then
sent back out again so you'd alleviate
all of that
if everything was sort of like trying to
get locally and obviously you'd have
some things that would
put to be not of getting grown somewhere
getting sent somewhere for packaging
because it's cheap labor
and then getting sent back and then sold
an uh
place so should we do away with all that
so i think local
local communities and people would
support local communities and
everything else and local farmers and
and stuff like that and get them away
from
these big bastards basically
i can go next or can share more if you
would like
um so what carrie had shared in the
beginning that she
shops based on price and not liking to
shop
that is very much me as well i went from
needing to buy organic and eating that
to being like well this i don't know how
much i can trust it and i'm really poor
and so i want food more than you know
and so i needed to change those values
and i think for me a perfect system is
one that that meets the consumer
game a triangle um that i want i want it
cheap fast and quality
and you can't actually have all three of
those so i want to be able to to decide
how to how to get those and i also
want the metrics from the good guide i
want to know is it healthy for me
does it hurt or help the planet and does
it help hurt or help the humans and
animals involved in the process
and to be able to do that in a way that
i don't have to shop where it can help
me figure out my recipes help me figure
out my food
which is the big part and um and then
help me
be like and these ones are here and
available locally right and if i want to
eat locally like
as a canadian and we're not supposed to
disagree with each other
but i i'm always worried about the
eating local movement because i'm like
wait where do i get almonds and bananas
and like there's a lot that i eat
that is can't really be grown in canada
at least with our current infrastructure
but to be able to say my value is i do
want to eat locally let's say 80
of my diet comes from local and in
season
and then i can choose yes and bananas
and almonds and offset them and see the
full
the full actual cost of the supply chain
so then i can make better decisions do i
really need bananas i don't know
um and have it as convenient as possible
and one app like one thing that feeds
all of that information to and makes it
as easy as possible yes taking pictures
taking pictures on the conveyor belt
where it's like we noticed you you're
buying cheerios here's an alternative
that's even
that's more within your values and
possibly produced locally
and i do think we can be more um more
efficient and see the loopholes
of where it makes sense to to come
together and create things like
factories and manufactured goods
when we can showcase that there's a um
a cost benefit analysis to it right as
game a as that is like once it makes
when i can stop giving my money to post
for for cheerios and
we can create cheerios ourselves and
they're organic and they take care of
the planet and the people
then i'm gonna switch over and i don't
really buy cheerios but that
that is um my i'm sure there's many
other things but that is
a good a good starting point for my
ideal five ten years in the future
i'm also muted to tell you you're muted
mark
thank you um as you were talking
i was um i was i was taking notes so i'm
taking those
to all of this um some things
came up i and um
they're fairly like a consistent thread
throughout some of them
came up i never never thought of and
that
see see recipes as well i
i think well that would be a cool little
add-on and maybe that
is something that could lever this
towards something that we never thought
of
another thing that you said jubilee was
uh
notice your buying habits and i thought
why the
hell would you want that when that's one
of the things that um
we're kind of concerned about now but
then
it went back to the trust idea that was
mentioned by everyone as well
so if this was good if you
felt that it was good that it it
you could see as kerry was saying that
the big companies and the bastards that
were buying
all buying up all the good ones start to
go bankrupt
because of this then you would start to
trust it a little bit more
i i would like to see all of that
plus the one app one place for
everything
and i would like to see this
um i don't even know what the word for
it would be
so ideally there would be a module
and the module would be created
so that and i did a little bit of
programming not a lot of programming
but the model would be created so that
um
uh in in microsoft they have these
dynamic linked libraries and things like
that but
it would be much more than that it would
be uh
something that you you would hand to the
companies like a dynamic link libraries
and say hey
fill this out and so they
they would put all that information in
there but if they weren't
as transparent as it
could be
and the cheapest this cheap matters to
me too
like something a good value and i could
see
where all the money was going in one app
so i could make my buying decision
because i
i want to make i want to feel confident
i don't feel confident now
so i i want to feel confident that that
purchase i'm making
is really doing all those things it's
lifting up
the small companies so i can i can
more readily make that trust that trust
judgment i guess and um
it's making it hard for somebody else to
fake and as i go and go around in the
world
um i see other people doing that same
thing
and i see the immediate results of of
those actions like
more local companies um less
big companies less driving less
less brainwashing less less predatory
marketing
because they will see that's ineffective
and they will try and uh emulate or die
so that's ideally for me that's what i
want to see
awesome now we can switch over to the
last section because they all kind of go
together anyway
um like everything comes up in the last
section we also go back to how it's
currently
and how we would like it to be um and i
think if if you're okay with them aren't
keeping it at ten thousand
hundred thousand dollars just because
although there aren't ten thousand
people in game a oh sorry
game b there's absolutely ten thousand
people in game a who care about
purchasing proper like care about
purchasing with their values i'm
pretty sure good guide had ten thousand
people using it and so
creating something within that space
it'll just give us more money and people
to play with
so what could we create to help people
vote with their wallets with ten
thousand people and a hundred thousand
dollars and while mark was talking there
was the two
the food part and we've had solution
raisings on food before
it would be instrumental because it's
where
none of us cannot right we either need
to grow our own or buy it like we
we can't not have food and the other
place i would like to see solutions
personally
is in the electronic sphere where
there's basically no real solution but
just seeing
the supply chain but i feel like those
are two different products
but creating them in a together tech way
um where there is um
like a central pool of data means in the
future they could be one app
but in the that's where my mind goes
like if it could work for both the
electronics
how do i make this purchase how do i
make sure it lasts and how do we like
keep
so i don't have four laptops all of
which are on their last leg
uh and food how do i make sure i'm
getting my body the nutrition it needs
well not hurting the planet
and um able to work together to to do
that with corporations that exist
and my neighbors and locally
um i don't know what that looks like ten
thousand people hundred thousand dollars
but what are some ideas that we could do
with that
okay well i'll i'll go with ten thousand
people obviously
that you would have a an established
network
right so half of these people would be
interested in maybe
becoming investigative reporters to
distribute
on them who's doing what where the when
you don't really maybe have time to do
that so
a lot of people might have time to
actually go and research the companies
and develop that information and
obviously
within that 10 000 there'd be so like
someone there who could actually build
an app
that would be useful and then obviously
within the ten thousand you'd have to
ask them
what questions that are important to
them so
you basically have to have something
like reason score um
with elections and solution raisins all
in one go
right so i'd have so like an
amalgamation
of that but as i said the app would sort
of contain that but you'd obviously need
to give those ten thousand people a say
in and
and find out what they do and what
they'd be interested in doing
maybe you know like you get these
mystery detectives who go to stores
and spy on them or that and then go back
you know i mean like mystery shoppers
and stuff like that as well so i think i
think if you can marry the
the tough part with with with the
hundred thousand well as i said if
you have ten thousand people who are
willing to give you ten dollars
or ten whatever it is a month then as i
said by the end of the year you'd have
1.2 million dollars so
i think with that money you could
actually create something but obviously
to be
and you'd need a community as well with
that app because people
like to sort of get to know each other
you know i mean and stuff like that as
well so
there'd be a lot of resources that might
not be thought of that would come
on top of the money as well so you
wouldn't know until you got the people
but that's
i suppose that'll be that'd be kind of
nice that that would
that would be my idea i love it here i
feel like you're creating all the game
be there
focus on which it seems to be happening
more and more often which i both love
what can we do at ten thousand people
and a hundred thousand dollars to most
powerfully help them
vote with their wallets right whether
they have a say in it or not
what could that look like right what
could ten thousand two hundred thousand
dollars
one of the things feeding off the food
piece that i would like the most access
to
is like the good guide actually focuses
on food and
beauty products and household cleaners
stuff that have ingredient lists
and ingredient lists are readily
available
they're like legally you have to publish
them
and the end they have a certain quality
to them
like if you have fragrance in your
ingredient list that is so the
corporations could get
um away with not telling you that
there's toxic sludge in here that's
going to give you cancer
and hurt your endocrine system and all
that because fragrance is just easier
than our like
a chemical so
anytime those those arbitrary
ingredients are used they get the worst
rating unless you're going to tell us
what that fragrance is we're going to
assume it's the toxic ones we're going
to assume it's the
other ones that having a way to
um qualify quality
quantify and qualify the ingredients
themselves
and then the product is just an
amalgamation of the ingredients and if
that's the case then anyone with
expertise can put in
the ingredient information like is so
how healthy is salt depends on the
quantity
but there's other things that are more
carcinogenic and such that there's um
something about dealing with the
ingredient list that then feeds into and
anyone can put in ingredients right i
can add any product to it
because all i've got to do is take a
picture of the product say what it is
and take a picture of the ingredients
and then
amalgamation putting those together to
see what is the health impacts what is
the
environmental impacts and then the cost
right the cost would be different no
matter where it is
if i buy it at this superstore versus
this one
customers could put that information and
i could be able to
show up on price as well
so is that um
that's going all back to kerry's idea of
the 10 000 investigative reporters
actively seeking out that information
and putting it into this
this list is that kind of what you had
carried that
well it will attentive because as i said
if you had a it has a network of 10 000
people
there's some people who are not going to
have very much time and there's some
people who are going to have a lot of
time
so the ones with a lot of time you could
get them involved by becoming
investigate reporters
and then they could report back on the
fine things and that and obviously the
ones with with no time
um obviously could find other ways of
sort of
contributing to to what what we're doing
and that no obviously within that
network there'd be some
programmers somebody wanted to actually
build something
so and then like it'd be like a circular
little circular economy within itself
you know what i mean so you could
actually get people to
to get involved start contributing in
whatever way
they could or whatever way they could
you know i mean so i think that would be
kind of powerful
because you'd have people who would
actually wanting to do it rather than
somebody oh well you must do this you
must do that
you know i mean so and i think you'd
find a balance there
of the people who are willing to like
get stuck in
you know what i mean and obviously if it
benefits them as well
and then obviously from out of that
we'll grow all sorts of little
connections and
crews and teams and all sorts of things
you know what i mean so
i've been having just that 10 thousand
people there's gonna be
people from all over the place people
you find in your local network you might
find they actually say oh by the way i'm
doing this do you wanna come join me to
the people they know
you know what i mean so so that would
that would create a we'd probably end up
with an army of lot a lot more people
um eventually but like
obviously we'd go for the ten thousand
first maybe the main
main ones but obviously it could grow
exponentially
without even having to try you know what
i mean so um
but yes that that'd be that'd be quite
good but as i said you've got to start
somewhere haven't you so
but you would need to structure that
network to
to benefit the people who's actually
joining
you know i mean so they feel like
they're involved and it's
that they're important for being there
and as i said the contributions that
they make towards it
and you know and because that will
create a sense of belonging
between the people and they'll be
wanting to share you know what i mean
like you see all these detective
um sleuths and armchair detectives and
that
and they're all getting in on it and
i've done this and you know i mean they
go out searching and stuff just
for things you know i mean so and i
think because it affects them
in terms of what they're eating and
what's in it you know
and so much like nobody trusts anybody
anymore especially within the corporate
world and
obviously people who go to shops don't
even like go into these shops but you
know there's nothing
you know walmart has taken all over the
wall you know so they've got a monopsony
that i found out that the word for it's
that way people have to
supply them because they're the only
ones you know i mean so um
so yeah so and i think a lot of people
would would end up and then you'd find
people who were as little
so they wanted to do their own
businesses within that
and go along with it with the the green
and helpful for the environment and that
and it would educate
and inspire a whole other things that we
we don't even know
so um so yeah so i've just gone off on a
tangent they'd have a like today so shut
up
i guess i haven't um participated yet in
this part
um i like all those ideas um
so yeah community driven
collection of information
and you know there'd be it'd have to be
supported
somehow so people would need to um
either pay or contribute data uh do the
investigation
maybe those people don't need to pay and
uh it would be
you know at the level of covering costs
um
not uh for profit
um in that in the traditional sense of
profit above all and
yes figuring out the details i think
kind of what we laid out is very very
complex so the next step would be
kind of like figuring out what's the
starting you know what are the steps to
get to that
so that's where my mind immediately goes
so uh we
we've expanded pretty well and then my
my natural tendencies
start narrowing again so but we may not
be ready for that yet
but i think all that all that we've
discussed kind of mirrors
um the thoughts i've had over the last
couple weeks during the discussions
and some things a while back when i said
oh i wish there was something
someplace i could go to actually look up
the information about these companies
and products
so yeah i guess i don't have much more
to add just uh yes let's do that
um bentley
you're you feel that this has gone as
wide as it
can uh
well uh maybe not i mean sometimes going
wider you can you could find a
brainstorming
thing but i'd i haven't heard a
diversity of ideas
except i mean we i yeah i think we've
kind of reached
i guess i do think we've kind of reached
the limit but i could be wrong about
that
and so now then it's more of just like
well which what order do we want to
start
building that and gathering people and
you know what are the steps
i i don't know i can't think of anything
wider but other people might
so if anyone i'm open no no i
i no this is important because i'm
trying to get a feel for it if it's gone
as
wide as you can there are some things i
heard here that i didn't hear
the last uh solution racing were eight
year old
and jubilee was there someone else it
was just three of you right you were
talking about that
there were some and i think it was an
idea from that too as well but there's
some new things here
um that thing that kerry was talking
about
oh yeah kerry was there on that one
yes
yeah yeah so the
the whole idea of the circular economy
within itself that's that's something
new
um the the people as
investigative reporters i was kind of
touched on but this is
this is much bigger it's it's kind of
like a minefield area
because how do you know and how do you
restrict so that when somebody put
something in that you can trust that
information so how do you how do you do
that
but i mean if you can empower them to
say you're an active piece of this
i think that is is kind of a cool and
powerful thing that might drive this
all on its own um so i think that that's
that's huge and that wasn't we didn't
kind of have that before so and there's
a
there's a few more things in here when
you talk about trusting ingredient lists
what what what that would look like and
having people
um if they don't put the actual
chemicals on the list
then they get a low score type of thing
so that's kind of my new show but
so mark i i can't expand it a little
more if you want
sure yeah so and so it depends on where
you want to
draw the line because uh
uh adriel is working on wikilection and
he has two other needs for a very
similar concept
which is politicians who are you going
to vote for right it's the same thing
but it's not
buying with your wallet so the same kind
of logical structure and maybe
system could be used to look is this
fault
politician voting based upon my values
and then should i vote for that
politician or should i
protest or or send them letters and
stuff like that
and then similar to the product space
which i wasn't sure how much we're going
to go down on like the quality of the
product
but i'm working with a group on no code
products
so there's there's a lot of new
technology in this space where people
can kind of build their own
technology products without having to
learn
actually how to write code there's a lot
of technologies you have to plug them up
together in certain ways
and sometimes the feature you want on
one thing doesn't go to the other so
but it has the same sort of thing as
like i need to balance price
and features uh and quality
um in a decision um but
those that that one's not necessarily
making the world a better place it's
very game a
the the wiki election is very kind of
game b
um but i i do think there's a need for a
generic
tool that says we as a community want to
take these entities whether people or
products or companies
and organizations and we want to rate
them on certain features
and then i want to be able to choose a
feature set that's important to me
and i guess i hadn't said this in the
thing but also be able to
to rank those so like let's say i'm
really care about the environment but
local is not that important to me but
this other person is like it's all about
local and you know i don't really think
the environment's that bad with some
yeah i don't know many people that they
but let's just say
um then they would get a different
product
set so i guess the part we didn't
mention was customizing
the um the result based upon my values
we probably touched on it but just be
more explicit so i
you know so i've been thinking this last
week to build a
you know some open open source code that
allows you to
build these sort of group feature
decision making group aggregate of data
but then individuals can make
decisions uh based off of it
so that's kind of the slightly bigger
scope
hey thank you
it's really kind of a new wiki for
because for me having i know we do not
have 10 000 people but
getting the threshold of people so you
can ask
them what they like what we just did
right how do you vote with your dollar
do you care about it at a company level
or a product level
and the answer for me is both but at the
same time which one is technology
technologically
better to access for like the cons the
individual
right am i going to look up a company or
am i going to look up a product i'm
probably
look up a product because that's what
i'm deciding to buy
and the products have the ingredient
information on them but that's again
my assumption is one person extrapolated
to ten thousand
it's not actually asking ten thousand
people and being like
would this work for no that sounds way
too hard i'm not going to take out my
app and scan things i will take a
picture of the serial aisle yeah that
sounds easy enough for me
that there's feedback into it so that
whatever the first part is
if people aren't using it there's a
reason why because i know when i was
using the good guide the fact that i
wasn't able to put in products
i'm like oh this isn't in here i okay i
can't even tag it i can't even be like
could you put this
in it's just not in there and
you know they don't again they're not
transparent on what it is
and i feel like that's possibly i don't
think they would sell it because they
got bought and then put on the shelf so
i'm definitely sure they wouldn't sell
us their information for a hundred
thousand
but that is part of what is like with
ten thousand people and a hundred
thousand dollars maybe it's more than
ten dollars a month
maybe it is that one point two million
right maybe it's the um
years wage to buy it from them and be
like hey we have ten thousand people and
put in ten dollars a month we'll buy it
over the next year and use your data and
use that
but we're going to make it fully
transparent i don't think i think the
old good guide would have sold it to us
i don't think the new good guide would
because they were basically bought by a
right wing
we don't want this to exist but we want
to oh my god
which shows that they were powerful
and so like like you mentioned like i
think it'd be difficult to get down like
you said if it's not in there and you
can put it in there but still if you get
in there 90
is not in there there's no you're not
getting any value out of putting the
stuff in there for a while and
everything you've put in you don't care
about you put it in you already have the
data
um uh so
um so yes that's kind of the tough thing
and i guess
just kind of as a short step to that
would be
if you scan it in or take a picture of
the aisle maybe we can pull out well
and that's actually pretty that's
technologically possible but that's
challenging code too but
like let's say you're shopping online
and it was just a plug-in that whenever
you're
you're you see like even the the google
or
go product results it would highlight
ones that
were the companies meet your values but
we're not sure about the products yet
and that would be the first iteration
and later on we go down to the products
so it'd still probably be at the product
level that
like julie like said that that's that's
where
people are actually integrating with the
thing it just we just
it just may be a while before we get
down to that level of data but
yeah but maybe it's not useful until you
get down to that level of data
well i i when when i think about it
and i don't know if it's if it's useful
i guess you guys can weigh in on this
is to me the the first primary use would
be
in in putting small companies in there
so the smaller ones that we kind of have
an idea that they're doing the right
thing anyways
and the local companies in here so maybe
what the 10 000 people could do is
um fill out this module
and start with the smallest companies
so your your efforts as part of this
army is to to get us
a hundred thousand small companies
and hopefully from that
we can have a kind of a movement where
people
start buying with their wallets because
this app will show them
we'll start with these smaller companies
we will
we could present those modules to the
larger companies and say
if you fill these out you'll become
part of this this it's kind of a larger
buying group and
i don't know why the good guy didn't get
around much i don't know why
i didn't find why was it not on my radar
you know because i i was
buying consciously and i was constantly
looking for
places where i could find that but if we
had
10 000
people that were active in this like
could that grow to 100
000 and if so then what what would that
look like what would it take
to have it grow to 100 000 concentrating
on the smaller companies
and then allowing for the larger
companies
to become part of that list
and maybe that's that's how it will grow
so then
the companies that got on there first
would receive a larger a better score
companies that had a greater
transparency would
receive a better score and then this so
this app would show it all to you would
show
where all the ones closest locally to
you are
and there would be a way to put that
information in but it would have to be
vetted in some way i'm not sure how so
that
we know that the information going in um
a marketplace kind of platform
like i know you can create your own
marketplace on that for the green
companies
for the ones who we actually trust uh so
that you know not not
screwing them out loads of money for
just being there but they could go in
and maybe they could pay a little
subscription that would help towards
keeping you know the marketplace or they
could pay towards the marketplace in
terms
of you know um something like that as
well so i'm just talking shit now so
yeah like i think but i think in in when
i envisioned this
i envisioned this as a marketplace
because
when you were talking about it before
you talked you talked about i think your
words were
a circular economy within itself and you
were talking about
um um the people are
willing to do what they are good at and
want to do
so what they're good at and want to do
is maybe as a small
company want to market with and get
their supplies from a company that they
can
see everything about
you know that so that kind of
marketplace would be created anyways
does that make sense kerry the closest
thing again
now to a marketplace is harrison and
colleen's
project i think which is like an online
market an online farmers market
that can be franchised to any local city
it just needs someone to come they're
not very technical like
it's not a beautiful website it's fairly
old-looking
but something about like those two
meeting of okay well there's the
farmer's market that already exists that
is very local but the people have to go
and sit there
for you know all of saturday after
they've picked their stuff
and there's you know do i know that this
local gem is or i don't know all the
same things we've talked about
but to be able to put like if it's a
marketplace we're looking to create
then we need to start from the
marketplace which means starting from
people producing the goods and saying
what is stopping you right is it the
marketing is it the customers
is it the um transportation that you
have to compete with right people are
coming to the farmers market they bring
goods home how do you get them if you
don't stay in the farmer's market how do
you get the bits to them
and meeting the needs of the small
businesses in a way that works for the
consumer
um that is that price triangle right how
the expense which is maybe not what
we're sticking with but it's still there
the convenience and the quality
and asking the um
like i feel like the transparency of the
farmer's market is kind of where you
start
it's not you know what i mean i i know
that if the far people are there at the
farmer's market the farmer's market has
vetted them a little bit
um and then i can ask questions of them
and start that relationship and having
that online farmers market that online
market
and then starting that dialogue to say
well here's what i can wait wait did you
spray the blueberries i want to know and
like yes i did on this day and like well
how can we get a bigger picture
like starting with something like
harrison and colleen's and then but
again that's just
food it might be i might um
maybe need a little clarification when
you're saying market
because when i think of market i think
of a
place where you're actually doing the
transactions
which for me creates a barrier of entry
for the businesses if they have to put
their inventory
or their sales through this channel then
that's a high barrier
um so i would rather start with an
information platform and then if we
want if people want to start selling on
it then that would be a second that
would be the
a later step um
that's a good idea like all the together
text of all of the stuff coming out of
game b it's like there's this miraculous
future technology blah that like solves
everything
but they like it's all chicken and egg
and that it's like okay we're all
approaching it from different places
like do we need it to be
company product or market start with one
of them they'll all come
and that's the thing with any of our
projects is it's like right we're
solving that 10 years down the road
but right now it's like start with one
thing and then yes
it will grow into this beautiful bluff
later but yeah except the company review
side is 20 thousand dollars a market is
a hundred thousand dollars and uh you
know
the the cost between those several
solutions are dramatically exponentially
different and i know there are tools to
build a quote market but then you have
to market the market
and it takes a lot of effort so the
total effort is still higher even though
the cost of the
that specific tool is low so i
i think we can do all those things but i
don't think it's
just pick one at the pick the one that's
is the easy the lowest effort won first
and build
and i think that would be uh
that would be by i think that would be
by
a company although mark's idea of
starting with small
companies is something i'd never thought
of and now the more i think about the
better that that
is because it hits on exactly what
what we want to accomplish it gives
people a good feeling like the
detectives that kerry brought up
is that they're promoting a local
business
when they do this so there's value in
doing it even if you're not getting
anything out of it right
so now we have value for the
participants we have value for the
business and we have value for the users
all made
with without a high bar we don't you
don't have to have every small business
and the whole word for this
provide value if i go in and i find two
small businesses
and my whole dfw metroplex of millions
of people
that's that's a value to me that's
suddenly
so that's i don't know i was intrigued
by that
it'd be interesting even in vancouver to
know even if it's just
food and just local what that looks like
like what and that was where like
calling that's what colleen and harrison
kind of do
but for their local one and then they
figured out that you can
they have a process i think to work
through to when you franchise it
um and there are local
growing co-ops and things like that
so you could even kind of put the data
in for just those and you'd cover
a wide variety i i'd look to see to make
sure there isn't
that this already isn't there
because it's almost too easy but
again the problem with all the mvps is
they already exist they've already
happened and they already failed
but if we're creating something that
gets better and better and you're
creating it with the threshold of people
then you don't have the same problems
they did but we
right now have all the same problems
they did yeah so maybe one of the steps
would be for us to
research the past experiments and and
digest that
learnings now yeah definitely
i i was writing as as everybody was
speaking so
there there's a couple of things that
that that jumped out at me
is it it seems like
jubilee and kerry you you you really
there's a fire in you for this kind of
marketing that
could occur within the space that's
created
but i don't think i think that marketing
can still go on
[Music]
and and maybe it's even more effective
but doesn't have to
be it doesn't have to be closed within
that space but it can be begun within
that space so you can say
here's everything about us just take a
look at us and you'll see
and you can go down the rabbit hole and
find out everything about a company
and then i'm you find out everything
about it here in hollow chain
when i i just went on their site and to
have a look at it again
it can provide a lot of that just one
example
but then all of a sudden now you have
this
this is how this is a snapshot of this
in real time if anything changes
it becomes gray and some things change
and we can't
trust the same way until it's cleared up
but if we can have that
then that is a really really good place
to do marketing
kind of outside of that space but it can
be the
actual contact and the actual trust can
be established there
and then you go out of the space to just
finish it up
iron the details outside and then later
on maybe
because because everything is there
later on
you can build those kind of smart
contracts and well holochain does that
anyways but
you can do that later on because and
maybe that's what you do
is you build it just like tesla builds
cards now that so they
they can all be self-driving all of
those things
could possibly be built with those
ability
for to create those contracts and
exchange funds
right within the market but that you
don't have to have that in the beginning
you just start with the small companies
and and they get
all the benefit and everything that you
you want to give
personal time uh
priority on the space especially for if
they go
as transparent as possible and all of
that
will promote them to the top and you
would know so if we had 10 000 people
doing two of these
you know all of a sudden you'd have 20
000 small build businesses around the
world that you would know
everything about and that that would be
a powerful start for you
yeah and like if we solved marketing
then finding those ten thousand be like
there's ten thousand people out there
easily who would be willing to put in
time to just research two companies
especially if it wasn't super arduous
process
um but how do you find those ten
thousand people right marketing but like
we have to solve marketing if we get
marketing
but um so we're at the hour for sure um
i'd like to go around and share what you
think is the most powerful thing we
could do
that we've talked about or that comes to
you in the moment that is within the
umbrella of um
not needing more than 10 000 people and
100 000
to start it
i can start um so i i would like to
start a small business directory based
on what mark
said that starts um
allowing you to filter those small
businesses also by your
um by your values um
but um so i'd like to build that
directory as a start
and and i think that could be done
within those constraints easily
and populated with enough info to
provide sustainable value
absolute opposite i love that idea but
i'm also the opposite row
of like a place where i could put in
ingredients where there's 10 000 people
who can take a picture of the
ingredients because then we have at
least
same thing 10 000 products is at least
what you're starting with um
to look at does it if it doesn't contain
something i care about then
it's as easy as taking a picture of the
product and taking a picture of the
ingredient list
and um doing the work only for the
ingredients
just is salt good it's all bad where
does it normally come from until the
company can prove it
does it not through that that horrible
method then you get the
verbal metric that having just a space
for ingredients
leads into a lot of the other things
but company and ingredients one or the
other
together about you carrie and mark what
do you think is the most powerful one
yeah i'm just typing here um
i i i go back to um i guess a
conglomerate of what everybody was
saying the the idea of
just having something where
we could put in get those 10 000
investigative reporters putting in as
much information as they can
and and make it make it something that's
doable for them
something that's easy
and so we have that list what bentley
said makes sense to me
um but also make it where it's where
it's expandable so
we we have the code in there so we can
expand to put
all those other things in there but uh
start with the the modules get uh ten
thousand people doing uh two companies
each
and so we have those products on there
we have the modules
the companies can if they change can
update it and then we have our ten
thousand investigators look at it and
see
must change if people are actually doing
what they say
well yeah i'd like him that and um
what bentley said about the directory
but i think with that would come a
library
a library guide of how to's how to go
and investigate a company how to make
sure
that you're finding out you know what i
mean because i think if you give them
because if you said to everybody
who you knew would you be interested in
in finding out
what what a company says is what it says
on the tin
but also in a way that's so they're good
for the environment
because i think you'll find there's
thousands of people out there
who are just getting so pissed off with
being bullshitted
about everything that they if they could
take it into their own hands and have a
how-to guide and have people who they
knew we were doing the same thing
that would be really good for them so
that would help in in developing
the the app and and the questions and
everything else as well
and having something like a directory
and a wii guide
you know what i mean and this is the
project we're doing and this is what we
want to do are you look for this and
then
create the mailing list and then you
know i mean then that starts
you know what i mean like a boot camp
for the um the
the um what what did you call them
depending investigative reporters
i like the ideas similar to what i'm
trying to do with solution raising
of um like trickle in and somehow we'll
get 10 000 people that actually aren't
like
actually kind of works for a company
directory
because instead of you're paying ten
dollars a month or ten dollars per
project which i'm still doing solutions
is still powerful and awesome but
having right like if i sign up to do
that it doesn't matter if we're the
first four
if i'm committing to do one company a
month i don't know how hard it is
um right then like in a year we have
12 if i'm only one person i 48 if it's
all four you don't like that there's a
i just do whatever that there's a way
to um keep adding that information
yes the information is going to change
but if the business is still in business
which is maybe actually that's in this
time period a little little risky but
like that's there's still the directory
it's building
or in if you'd started with products
then starting that right i'm putting 10
products
a month until we will not launch until
we have x amount right
company director we're not going to
launch until we have 10 000 or 20 000
companies
well well what i was going to say
because i'm building a kind of a project
listed site
for on drupal and that i could actually
do a a wee prototype if you wanted
um with that because i'm just learning
um how to do a proper listen and make it
look nice and all that
that could be one of the tabs that i
could add to the site
just as as a start off without it
costing us anything
you know i mean that would do a
directory from that if you wanted and
also put
like guides and principles and how to
use if you could build those first
and have that there and then you know
you could have a page set up
so it's just for that because i because
part of the project thing i was doing
mark was having a project of coming out
of game b
of what's that and the proj about the
project and you could have that out in
the open so
people outside and then you could say
well this is what i'm working on
this is who's involved blah blah blah
you know what i mean and then
you know and as i said if you put if you
give them a source like a set of guides
and how to's now would you um go and
what questions would you need to ask and
how do you find out the information
and stuff like that as well and then you
can show it to people and i say oh yeah
i'm up for that and then you know become
become a private dick
[Laughter]
no they can't drive a dick that like
want to be a private sector well maybe
not but um
you know i just want to stop you for
once i can carry um worth the hour i'm
just going to
stop the recording now so this will be
the end of my party
after that all right thanks for joining
for the
solution raising on vote with your
wallet